{"tossups": [{"question": "A modi\u3ec8cation of this technique is based on the activation of Ras (\"rahs\") when hSos (\"h-sauce\") is localized to the cell membrane. Three-amino-one-two-four-triazole, or 3-AT, can be used to evaluate expression of the HIS3 (\"hiss-three\") reporter in this method. The transcription factor used in this technique is also used with its upstream activation sequence to induce targeted gene expression in Drosophila. A form of this technique applicable in mammals involves the phosphorylation of g\u00c2\u00b7p\u00c2\u00b7130 by T\u00c2\u00b7Y\u00c2\u00b7K\u00c2\u00b72 and is known as the Kinase Substrate Sensor, or KISS. It can be extended to integral membrane proteins by using \"Cub\" and \"Nub\" protein domains in the split-ubiquitin system. It involves expression of a reporter gene when the activation domain and DNA-binding domain of transcription factor Gal4 (\"gal\" \"four\") are brought together by bait and prey proteins. For 10 points, name this technique that involves using S. cerevisiae to identify protein-protein interactions.", "answer": "yeast 2-hybrid assay [or Y2H]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>yeast 2-hybrid assay</u></b> [or <b><u>Y2H</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["yeast 2-hybrid assay", "Y2H"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Lionel Trilling contrasted the liberal reception of this author with that of Henry James in his polemical essay \"Reality in America.\" Stuart Sherman emphasized this writer's ethnic heritage in essays attacking his fiction as \"barbaric\" and exemplifying a kind of \"animalism.\" This novelist is depicted as a boy \"staring at the door of the crawfish's burrow\" and as a man who \"watched for men and women hiding in burrows of fate amid great cities\" in a portrait of him as \"the Poet\" by his friend Edgar Lee Masters, who included it in the Spoon River Anthology. His early works were championed by his friend and sometimes editor H. L. Mencken, though they quarreled over his novel about the painter Eugene Witla, The \"Genius\". Sinclair Lewis said that \"the first fresh air since Mark Twain and Whitman\" was brought to America by this man's novel depicting the downfall of George Hurstwood. For 10 points, name this pioneer of American naturalism who wrote Sister Carrie.", "answer": "Theodore Dreiser [or Theodore Herman Albert Dreiser]", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Theodore Dreiser</u></b> [or <b><u>Theodore Herman Albert Dreiser</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Theodore Dreiser", "Theodore Herman Albert Dreiser"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This philosopher called for a \"vocabulary of attention\" in \"Against Dryness,\" citing Simone Weil, whose concept of decreation this philosopher translated as \"unselfng.\" In the first English monograph on Sartre, this philosopher rejected the idea of morality as \"shopping\" in favor of a Platonic concept of \"vision.\" This philosopher's major work begins with the essay \"The Idea of Perfection,\" which contains a thought experiment in which a mother-in-law M comes to a new moral understanding of her daughter-in-law D. This author's Metaphysics as a Guide to Morals expands on themes she introduced in The Sovereignty of Good. She was the subject of an \"Elegy\" by her husband John Bayley, who was hurt by her long-term a\u3ec8fair with the author of Natural Goodness, Philippa Foot. For 10 points, name this English philosopher who also wrote such novels as A Severed Head and The Sea, The Sea.", "answer": "Iris Murdoch [accept Jean Iris Murdoch]", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Iris Murdoch</u></b> [accept <b><u>Jean Iris Murdoch</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Iris Murdoch", "Jean Iris Murdoch"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A technique in this field starts with the introduction of the unnatural amino acid A\u00b7H\u00b7A into a protein. SPANC (\"spank\") reactions, where 1,3 nitrones and DIBO combine to generate N-alkyl\u00b7ated isox\u00b7azolines, is a popular approach in this field. A strain-promoted version of a reaction in this paradigm was first developed as a faster alternative to the Staudinger ligation. The anti-Markovnikov thiol\u00b7ene and thiol\u00b7yne reactions have experienced a recent revival for their applicability this field. Carolyn Bertozzi pioneered the use of cyclo\u00b7octyne in the \"copper-free\" segment of this field. Bio\u00b7orthogonal reactions utilize techniques from this paradigm within living systems. This paradigm is exemplified by the copper-one-catalyzed three-plus-two cyclo\u00b7addition between an alkyne and an azide; that reaction is named for Rolf Huisgen (HOY-jen). For 10 points, name this chemical paradigm that emphasizes modular units and bio\u00b7mimetic reactions and is championed by K. Barry Sharpless.", "answer": "click chemistry [or bio-orthogonal chemistry]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>click chemistry</u></b> [or <b><u>bio-orthogonal chemistry</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["click chemistry", "bio-orthogonal chemistry"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A hawthorn branch from this town that unusually flowers in the winter as well as the spring is a traditional gift to the monarch. Iron oxide deposits under this town give the water of one of its wells a reddish hue, leading to legends about the healing properties of the well. It contains the ruins of the Benedictine Abbey of St. Mary, which according to legend became the First Christian church in England when it was founded by Joseph of Arimathea, who brought the Holy Grail to this town. In 1191, monks digging here discovered the supposed graves of Arthur and Guinevere. Only the tower of St. Michael's Church remains atop the terraced conical \"tor\" that towers over this town. This town neighbors the town of Pilton, where a \"Pyramid Stage\" is annually built for a major musical festival. For 10 points, name this town in Somerset, England that is sometimes identified as the mythical Avalon.", "answer": "Glastonbury", "subcategory": "Mythology", "category": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Glastonbury</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Glastonbury"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This group's last great fortress was taken with bullhide-covered sabat tunnels by a commander who built statues of their teenage heroes, Jaimal and Patta. This group enforced unilineal inheritance, with female infanticide o\u3ec8ten performed by smearing opium onto the mother's nipples; its women also committed mass suicide in the jauhar ritual a\u3ec8ter defeat. A\u3ec8ter losing to Muhammad Ghori at the Battle of Tarain, these people consolidated their holdings behind fortress cities like Chitor and Ajmer. Communities of these people were broadly divided into the \"Sun People,\" \"Moon People,\" and \"Fire People.\" Some historians believe that their dominant Gurjara clan migrated from Central Asia in the 7th century a\u3ec8ter the White Huns. Under Rana Sanga, they lost the Battle of Khanwa to Babur, whose grandson Akbar built Fatehpur Sikri to celebrate their conquest. For 10 points, name this loose constellation of Hindu warrior clans that controlled much of modern-day northern India, and whose territories are now called Rajasthan.", "answer": "Rajputs", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Rajputs</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Rajputs"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A taxi driver learns about a treacherous act he committed during this historical event in the last past life narrative of Susan Barker's The Incarnations. During this event, a girl kicks the pregnant Nini in the stomach until she gives birth; a\u3ec8ter this event, that girl cannot speak during her public execution because her vocal cords are cut in the novel The Vagrants. In reaction to this event, the muckraking series \"People or Monsters?\" was published, and the literary journal Today was founded to champion writings of the \"Misty Poets.\" The short story \"The Class Monitor\" pioneered a genre of literature de\u3ec8ned by re\u3ec8lections on this historical event, called \"scar literature.\" During this event, The Legend of the Red Lantern was popularized as one of \"Eight Model Plays,\" and the author of the play Hai Rui (\"high\" rway) Dismissed From Oa\u03043ce was censored. For 10 points, name this period of political upheaval in China in which Red Guards sought to restore Maoist ideology.", "answer": "the Great Proletarian Cultural Revolution", "subcategory": "Other Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>the Great Proletarian Cultural Revolution</u></b>", "acceptable": ["the Great Proletarian Cultural Revolution"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Minor details of this artwork include a half-submerged horse with \u3ec8lippers crawling onto the shore and the head of an elephant coming out of the ground. In this work, two rams' heads decorate the ends of a boat that is supported by angry-looking \u3ec8sh. At the base of this work, reclining male nudes in \u3ec8lowing red robes represent the times of the day, and four men shown from the waist up with pu\u3ec8fed cheeks represent the winds. In this sculpture, green enamel is used to color the earth, which holds up a temple on which a naked woman is reclining. In 2003, Robert Mang stole this sculpture, which is a rare piece of metalworking by its artist that hasn't since been melted down or lost. In this 26-centimeter high sculpture completed at Fontainebleau, blue enamel is used to represent the sea where Neptune holds up a trident opposite Ceres. For 10 points, name this precious piece of gold tableware designed for Francis I by Benvenuto Cellini.", "answer": "The Saltcellar of Francis I [or the Saliera]", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Saltcellar of Francis I</u></b> [or the <b><u>Saliera</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["The Saltcellar of Francis I", "Saliera"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Jan Tarnowski (yahn tar-NOV-ski) adapted these military items for use with Polish hussars to obliterate 10,000 Moldavians at the Battle of Obertyn. These items were close cousins of the gulyay gorod used by Ivan the Terrible to conquer the Khanate of Kazan. A tactic when soldiers were out of gunpowder was to use these items to crush enemies beneath an avalanche of stones. Their use by the Ottoman Empire dates from the Battle of Varna, where Julian Cesarini's argument to employ them overcame sounder advice from John Hunyadi. A fake retreat that enticed the \"Orphans\" to abandon these objects led to the killing of Prokop the Great by Catholic forces at the Battle of Lipany. Most useful on long, level terrain, they were hooked together with chains and manned by handgun-wielding peasants, who \u3ec8red on the feudal cavalry of Emperor Sigismund. These weapons were arranged in squares to form mobile fortresses called tabor that won the battle of Kutna Hora for Jan Zizka (YAHN ZHIZH-kuh). For 10 points, name these devices used by the Hussites, mobile vehicles which American pioneers \"circled\" in case of attack.", "answer": "war wagons [or tabor; or wagenburg; or laager]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>war wagons</u></b> [or <b><u>tabor</u></b>; or <b><u>wagenburg</u></b>; or <b><u>laager</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["war wagons", "tabor", "wagenburg", "laager"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This material makes up the undulating walls of the Atlantida Church and the other churches designed by Uruguayan architect Eladio Dieste. When Rotterdam's \"bouwcentrum\" (rhymes with \"now sent rum\") was torn down, a wall of this material was le\u3ec8t standing to preserve Henry Moore's Wall Relief No. 1. It was used by Roche and Dinkeloo to clad the four cylindrical towers of the Knights of Columbus headquarters. Louis Kahn famously told his students to talk to this material, which he used for the facades of his Richards Laboratory, Indian Institute of Management, and Phillips Exeter Library. It was a favorite of Alvar Aalto, who used it as the primary material for his Muuratsalo Experimental House and his Saynatsalo Town Hall. A thin, long, form of this material named a\u3ec8ter the Romans was used by Frank Lloyd Wright in the Robie House. For 10 points, name this material used in the facade of the Wainwright Building, which is traditionally made by heating a block of clay in a kiln.", "answer": "red brick [prompt on \"masonry\"]", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>red brick</u></b> [prompt on <u>masonry</u>]", "acceptable": ["red brick"], "promptable": ["masonry"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A monograph on this subject argues that it relies on \u3ec8ve \"sociological presuppositions,\" such as \"man's aim in life is happiness,\"and \u3ec8ve \"myths,\" such as that of \"the Youth;\" that book distinguishes its \"agitative\" from its \"integrative\" form, which is made necessary by technology. Harold Lasswell argued that action phrases and imperatives were grammatically characteristic of this practice, which he subjected to extensive content analysis. \"Flak\" and \"ownership\" are two of \u3ec8ve \u3ec8lters in a model named for this practice by Herman and Chomsky. This non-advertising practice is said to be inherently undemocratic in a book by Jacques Ellul, who disputed Edward Bernays' conclusion that this political practice, on which Bernays literally wrote the book in 1928, was necessary for democracy. Free \"People's Receivers\" and the \"Big Lie\" were techniques used as part of this practice in Nazi Germany. For 10 points, name this practice, mastered by Joseph Goebbels, of manipulating the public for political ends.", "answer": "propaganda [prompt on other answers, such as media manipulation or manufacturing consent, but the word propaganda is needed; do not accept or prompt on \"advertising\"]", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>propaganda</u></b> [prompt on <u>other answers, such as media manipulation</u> or <u>manufacturing consent, but the word propaganda is needed</u>; do not accept or prompt on \"advertising\"]", "acceptable": ["propaganda"], "promptable": ["other answers, such as media manipulation", "manufacturing consent, but the word propaganda is needed"], "rejectable": ["advertising"], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A form of this property manifests as the destruction of anti-nodal coherence peaks in the local density of states spectra of under-doped cuprate superconductors. Whether a certain quantity measuring this property obeys a conservation law di\u3ec8ferentiates Class A and Class B Hohenberg-Halperin models. Levin and Wen proposed string-net condensation as the generating mechanism for a form of this property associated with gapless boundary excitations that are robust against any local perturbations. The degenerate ground states observed in the fractional quantum Hall e\u3ec8fect possess that \"topological\" form of this property. The free energy is expanded in a power series as a function of a parameter named for this property in Lev Landau's theory of continuous phase transitions. For 10 points, name this property characterized by a correlation length that may be short-range or long-range.", "answer": "order [accept word forms; or charge order; or topological order; or order parameter; or short-range order; or long-range order; prompt on correlation or entanglement]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>order</u></b> [ accept word forms; or <b><u>charge order</u></b>; or <b><u>topological order</u></b>; or <b><u>order parameter</u></b>; or <b><u>short-range order</u></b>; or <b><u>long-range order</u></b>; prompt on <u>correlation</u> or <u>entanglement</u>]", "acceptable": ["order", "charge order", "topological order", "order parameter", "short-range order", "long-range order"], "promptable": ["correlation", "entanglement"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this novel, a professor tells his students to \"let your thought be the wall,\" then \"let your thought be that that thought the wall.\" Near the end of this novel, the protagonist writes in his journal that algebra \"deadens pain\" and re\u3ec8lects on illness, concluding that \"those who are well, and have to stand by and do nothing, also need help, perhaps even more than the sick.\" In accordance with his father's wishes, this novel's protagonist goes to Tennstedt to prepare for a job as a tax collector in the Directorate of Salt Mines. This novel's protagonist tells Karoline Just (KAR-oh-LEE-nuh YOOST) the beginning of a story about a young man's obsessive longing for the title object. At Gru\u0308ningen (GROO-nin-gen), the protagonist of this novel meets his twelve-year-old beloved, the terminally ill Sophie von Ku\u0308hn. For 10 points, name this novel about the young Fritz von Hardenberg, later known as Novalis, written by Penelope Fitzgerald.", "answer": "The Blue Flower", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Blue Flower</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Blue Flower"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A speech given about this personal attribute cites how \"Fuentes and McCa\u3ec8ferty\" died side by side with \"Bowie and Crockett\" at the Alamo. This individual attribute led its holder to condemn the statements of James P. Davis and James McManus against Luis Munoz Marin. Inveighing against this personal attribute diminished the public standing of the author of The Power of Positive Thinking, Norman Vincent Peale. In 2012, Rick Santorum claimed he wanted to \"throw up\" a\u3ec8ter reading a speech about this quality that a\u3ec8\u3ec8rmed Article VI of the Constitution to an audience in Houston. Although this quality's holder hoped that it was \"buried\" a\u3ec8ter defeating Hubert Humphrey in the West Virginia primary, this attribute may have lost its holder four states, including Ohio and Florida, to Richard Nixon. For 10 points, name this unique religious denomination held by the 35th President.", "answer": "the Catholicism of John Fitzgerald Kennedy [prompt on John F. Kennedy's religion; prompt on Catholicism]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>the Catholicism of John Fitzgerald Kennedy</u></b> [prompt on <u>John F. Kennedy's religion</u>; prompt on <u>Catholicism</u>]", "acceptable": ["the Catholicism of John Fitzgerald Kennedy"], "promptable": ["John F. Kennedy's religion", "Catholicism"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This man argued that the distribution of \"religious bene\u3ec8ts\" was a counterweight to political power caused by what he called \"hierocracies.\" He characterized Buddha as an \"exemplary prophet,\" unlike Muhammad, an \"ethical prophet.\" Werner Sombart challenged this man for characterizing Jews as a \"pariah-people\" whose business was limited to trade. This man's theory of strati\u3ec8cation considers market position, \"social honor,\" and political power as crystallized in the title entities of his text \"Class, Status, Parties.\" This man argued that politicians must balance their \"ethic of moral conviction\" with the everyday \"ethic of responsibility.\" He identi\u3ec8ed \"charismatic,\" \"legal,\" and \"traditional\" methods for state legitimation in a lecture that de\u3ec8nes the state as an entity that has a monopoly on legitimate violence. For 10 points, name this author of Economy and Society, \"Politics as a Vocation,\" and The Protestant Ethic and the Spirit of Capitalism.", "answer": "Max Weber [or Karl Emil Maximilian Weber]", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Max Weber</u></b> [or <b><u>Karl Emil Maximilian Weber</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Max Weber", "Karl Emil Maximilian Weber"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An essay titled \"New Notes on [this author]\" ridicules \"riddle-less sphinxes\" that yawn \"empty words\" whenever they see a book \"more amusing than the Iliad.\" A poem about this writer includes a line that T. S. Eliot translated as \"To purify the dialect of the tribe\" in \"Little Gidding.\" That poem about this writer describes him \"such as into himself eternity finally changes him.\" A work by this author displays two identical triangular \"symbolic circuits,\" whose occupants play at \"politics of the ostrich,\" according to a lecture interpreting its \"repetition automatism.\" Jacques Derrida's \"The Purveyor of Truth\" attacked Jacques Lacan for abusing psychoanalysis in a seminar on this author, whose \"Tomb\" is the subject of a poem by Stephane Mallarme\u0301. From 1847 to his death, Charles Baudelaire made a living translating and popularizing the works of this author, inspired by such stories as \"The Man of the Crowd.\" For 10 points, name this oft-translated American author of poems such as \"The Raven.\"", "answer": "Edgar Allan Poe", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Edgar Allan <b><u>Poe</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Edgar Allan Poe"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In 1788, rumors of the the\u3ec8t of these objects in New York provoked a mob that knocked out John Jay with an errant brick. John Rolph used whiskey barrels on Lake Ontario to smuggle these objects, which were o\u3ec8ten sold at the Fortune of War Public House. Two illegal traders in these goods were exposed thanks to the case of 'Da\u3ec8t Jamie,' a disabled boy on the streets of Edinburgh. In 1831, Thomas Williams, John Bishop, and James May sought to make a pro\u3ec8t by producing these objects, becoming nicknamed the \"London Burkers\" a\u3ec8ter two Scottish vendors of these commodities, Burke and Hare. In A Tale of Two Cities, the \"resurrectionist\" Jerry Cruncher is a vendor of these objects, which were o\u3ec8ten in scarce supply to hospitals. For 10 points, name these objects analyzed by Andreas Vesalius, William Harvey, and beginning medical students.", "answer": "cadavers [or corpses; or dead people]", "subcategory": "Other History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>cadavers</u></b> [or <b><u>corpses</u></b>; or <b><u>dead people</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["cadavers", "corpses", "dead people"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This man was the subject of two biographies by R.W. Southern, whose The Making of the Middle Ages argues that he was the origin of a genre of \"ardent and e\u3ec8fusive self-disclosure.\" At the Council of Bari, this man compared the relationship of the Father to the Son to that of man to himself through memory, an argument he published in On the Procession of the Holy Spirit. In a philosophical dialogue against an opponent named Boso, this man argues that the cruci\u3ec8xion was necessary not as a \"ransom,\" but as \"satisfaction\" for an a\u3ec8front to God. This author of Cur Deus Homo used the motto \"faith seeking understanding\" and famously wrote, \"I believe so that I may understand.\" This one-time Abbot of Bec invoked the \"fool of the Psalms\" in an argument that Gaunilo (gow-NIL-oh) responded to by postulating an imaginary island. In his Proslogion, this scholar began an argument with the claim that one can imagine the existence of the greatest possible conceivable being. For 10 points, name this Archbishop of Canterbury who formulated the ontological argument for the existence of God.", "answer": "St. Anselm of Canterbury", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>St. Anselm of Canterbury</u></b>", "acceptable": ["St. Anselm of Canterbury"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "n the fourth and \u3ec8nal movement of an F minor piece composed for this ensemble, a fugue climaxes on an unresolved C major chord followed by a bar of silence, then a return of the piece's opening theme. A set of 16 pieces composed for this ensemble was published with easy and hard versions arranged for solo performance. A set of six pieces for this ensemble ends with a tribute to Espan\u0303a, an orchestral rhapsody by the composer's friend Emmanuel Chabrier. Sixteen waltzes make up Brahms's Opus 39 for this ensemble, for which Schubert wrote a Fantasia in F Minor. Tendresse is the penultimate piece in a suite for this ensemble that includes Mi-a-ou (\"meow\", but stretched out) and was named for the daughter of the composer's mistress. A set of eight pieces originally composed for this ensemble is bookended by C major and G minor furiants. This is the ensemble for which Gabriel Faure's Dolly Suite and Antonin Dvorak's Slavonic Dances were written. For 10 points, name this ensemble, in which two pianists play the same piano.", "answer": "piano four hands [or a quatre mains; or a quattro mani; or zu vier Ha\u0308nden; or vierha\u0308ndig; prompt on piano duet; prompt on two pianists; prompt on duet; do not accept \"two pianos\"]", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>piano four hands</u></b> [or a <b><u>quatre mains</u></b>; or a <b><u>quattro mani</u></b>; or <b><u>zu vier Ha\u0308nden</u></b>; or <b><u>vierha\u0308ndig</u></b>; prompt on <u>piano duet</u>; prompt on <u>two pianists</u>; prompt on <u>duet</u>; do not accept \"two pianos\"]", "acceptable": ["piano four hands", "quatre mains", "quattro mani", "zu vier Ha\u0308nden", "vierha\u0308ndig"], "promptable": ["piano duet", "two pianists", "duet"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Anthony Hoare distinguished between \"angelic\" and \"demonic\" forms of programs with this property, depending on the program's likelihood to terminate. Solving the \"canonicity problem\" for a mathematical model that has this property is PSPACE-complete, whereas solving the \"canonicity problem\" for a model without this property is in NL. A \u3ec8nite model possessing and named for this property can be obtained by either the Glushkov or the Thompson constructions. A model of size n having this property may be replaced by an equivalent one lacking this property but having size as large as two to the n via the Rabin-Scott powerset algorithm. Adding this property to certain constructs does not increase the amount of languages they accept if the problem requires a polynomial amount of space to solve, according to Savitch's theorem. Epsilon transitions and multiple start states can be used to specify the \u3ec8nite state machines that possess this property. The satis\u3ec8ability problem and the zero-one integer programming problems are veri\u3ec8able in polynomial time on Turing machines that have this property. For 10 points, name this property that puts the \"N\" in the NP complexity class.", "answer": "nondeterministic [or word forms, such as nondeterminism]", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>nondeterministic</u></b> [or <b><u>word forms, such as nondeterminism</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["nondeterministic", "word forms, such as nondeterminism"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This technology was the driving force behind Operation Wilfred, a plan to cut off Nazi Germany from Narvik iron ore. The \"Crab,\" \"Scorpion,\" and \"Toad\" were devices o\u3ec8ten ftted with long chains that were designed to counter this technology. Charles Goodeve countered this technology by inducing an \"N-pole up\" field around his ships in a technique known as \"degaussing.\" Bernard Montgomery opened the Second Battle of El Alamein with Operation Lightfoot, a plan to counter this technology, which historians have proven was responsible for the Britannic incident of 1916. A variant of this device was nicknamed the \"Bouncing Betty.\" One of these devices, rather than a protege of Marcel Marceau, was responsible for the death of Lord Herbert Kitchener. For 10 points, name these self-contained explosives used to destroy ships and personnel during World War II.", "answer": "landmines [or sea mines]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>landmines</u></b> [or <b><u>sea mines</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["landmines", "sea mines"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}